Guide to the Bryant Bennett papers, 1767-1902 RL.10030
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bryant Bennett papers
1767-1902, bulk 1840-1875
bulk
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bennett, Bryant
RL.10030
2 Linear Feet
Bryant Bennett was a merchant and planter residing in Williamston, North Carolina (in Martin County). This collection contains correspondence and papers of Bryant Bennett and of his family. Included are mercantile accounts of the firms of Bennett and Hyman in Williamston, N.C. and of Bennett and Price in Hamilton (both places in Martin County), school letters from a normal school in Oxford, North Carolina, deeds, promissory notes, receipts for land sold for taxes, plantation account books containing household and farm accounts, lists of slaves and supplies issued to them, business records dealing with the marketing of cotton at Norfolk, Virginia, agricultural treatises by one S. W. Outterbridge of Martin County, and letters to Bennett after he had moved to Plymouth, North Carolina, in 1869.
Biographical note
Bryant Bennett was a merchant and planter residing in Williamston, North Carolina (in Martin County).
Collection Overview
This collection contains correspondence and papers of Bryant Bennett and of his family. Included are mercantile accounts of the firms of Bennett and Hyman in Williamston and of Bennett and Price in Hamilton (both places in Martin County), school letters from a normal school in Oxford, North Carolina, deeds, promissory notes, receipts for land sold for taxes, plantation account books containing household and farm accounts, lists of slaves and supplies issued to them, business records dealing with the marketing of cotton at Norfolk, Virginia, agricultural treatises by one S. W. Outterbridge of Martin County, and letters to Bennett after he had moved to Plymouth, North Carolina, in 1869.
Please note that all folder and item titles in this collection guide have been taken from card catalogs and other inventories created in the early 20th Century.
Provenance
The Bryant Bennett papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1933 and 1949.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Existence and Location of Copies
This collection has been microfilmed as part of Records of Antebellum Southern Plantations from the Revolution through the Civil War project, Series F.
North Carolina -- Economic conditions; Agricultural literature -- Southern States; Oxford (N.C.) -- History; Williamston (N.C.) -- History; Plymouth (N.C.) -- History; Plantations -- North Carolina; Merchants -- North Carolina; Slavery -- North Carolina; Cotton trade -- Southern States; Farm Management -- North Carolina; Bennett and Hyman (Williamston, N.C.); Bennett and Price (Hamilton, N.C.); Bennett, Bryant; Outterbridge, S.W.
- Bryant Bennett papers, 1767-1902, bulk 1840-1875
  Scope and Contents
  Please note that all folder and item titles in this collection guide have been taken from card catalogs and other inventories created in the early 20th Century.
  - Papers, 1767-1846; bbp010003; 2 folders (Box 1, Folder 1-1A)
  - Papers, 1847-1851; bbp010123 (Box 1, Folder 2-2A)
  - Papers, 1852-1853; bbp010335; 2 folders (Box 1, Folder 3-3A)
  - Papers, 1854-1863; bbp010546; 2 folders (Box 1, Folder 4-4A)
  - Papers, 1864-1869; bbp010753 (Box 2, Folder 1-1A)
  - Papers, 1870-1902 and undated; bbp010903; 2 folders (Box 2, Folder 2-2A)
  - Account Book, 1848-1851; bbp020001 (Box 2, Volume S:310)
  - Account Book, 1851; bbp020027 (Box 2, Volume S:311)
  - Negro Accounts [Title taken from card catalog created in the early 20th Century], 1855-1858; bbp020038 (Box 2, Volume S:312)
  - Negro Accounts [Title taken from card catalog created in the early 20th Century], 1860; bbp020071 (Box 2, Volume S:313)
  - Negro Accounts [Title taken from card catalog created in the early 20th Century], 1881-1883; bbp020092 (Box 2, Volume S:314)
  - Ledger, 1851-1868; bbp020106 (Volume 1)